[TEL]（シャッター音）
[TEL]（操作音）
（嘘界）これが　恙神　涯の…。
（涯）お前は　最初から
こちら側だったんだ。→
どうして　人間と
寄り添えると思った？　化け物。
（嘘界）う～ん。
何か違うんですよね。
♪♪～
So this is Gai Tsutsugami's...
You've belonged to this side from the beginning.
Why did you think you could
cuddle up to some human?
You monster.
Mmm, it's just not quite right...
"Deleting Data"
A symphony of disintegration resounds
The falling rain has the exact timbre of tears
Realize
Those eyes are for recognizing each other with
Those voices are for
conveying our feelings with
Those hands are for joining
hands with our loved ones
All you living beings who can hear this song
The truth lies within your heart
And even when you're traveling a stormy sea
It will give you a strength
That will never flinch
（操作音）
Atonement
≪（扉の開く音）
I'm sorry, Mana.
（春夏）ごめんね　真名ちゃん。
あっ！　そんな…。
ここに　いるはずじゃ？
What?! But she should be here!
（茎道）真名は　ここには　いない。
最初からな。
Mana's not here. She never has been.
（茎道）お前は変わらないな　春夏。
You never change, Haruka.
自分に正直で　理想家で　諦めない。
You're honest with yourself,
and you're an idealist who never gives up.
まるで　あいつ…。
桜満クロスのように。
Just like him... like Kurosu Ouma.
You're the one who killed him, aren't you...
あなたが　あの人を殺したのよね。
兄さん。
（茎道）知っていたのか。
...Brother.
So you knew.
Why? You were best friends!
（春夏）どうして？
親友だったんでしょ。
フッ！　親友？
俺と　あいつが？
"Best friends"? Me and him?
Come on, hands in the air.
≪ほら　手を上げろ。
な…　何ですか？
僕が何したっていうんですか。
What is it? What do you think I've done?
（集）動かないでください。
Please don't move.
（亞里沙）あっ…。　あなた！
You...
Is this revenge for betraying you?
あなたを裏切った
復讐というわけ？
I don't care about me.
僕のことは　どうでもいい。
いのりの居場所を教えてください。
Tell me where Inori is, please.
Her?!
あの女の！？
（呼び出し音）
（ダアト将校）「全部隊に通達」→
Attention all units. Dr. Haruka Ouma
「桜満　春夏博士が
重大な反逆行為を犯し　逃走中」→
has committed high treason and is now on the run.
「各員　発見しだい
逮捕されたし」→
Anyone who finds her is to arrest her on sight.
「繰り返す。　桜満　春夏博士が
重大な反逆行為を犯し　逃走中」→
I repeat: Dr. Haruka Ouma
has committed high treason and is now on the run.
「各員　発見しだい　逮捕されたし」
Anyone who finds her is to arrest her on sight.
（嘘界）うん？
（嘘界）《あれは
セフィラの機密用ケース？》
That's one of the cases Sephirah
uses to transport top secrets...
ハハハハ。
ハハハ！
どうした？
What's so funny?
（嘘界）ぴんときた。
きてしまったんですよ。
It's all clear! I'm afraid
it's all clear to me now!
Mr. President, about Dr. Ouma...
閣下。　ドクター桜満の追跡→
ぜひ　私に
お任せいただきたいのですが。
I would dearly love to be
the one you send to track her.
≪（エンジンの始動音）
同志　亞里沙。　どこへ？
Where are you going, Comrade Arisa?
桜満博士を追います。
涯には　私から報告します。
I'm going after Dr. Ouma. I'll tell Gai myself.
W-Wait! You didn't say "Master"!
（ダアト将校）ま…　待て！
涯さまを呼び捨てに！
Let me speak with Haruka Ouma
once we find her. Understood?
発見したら
桜満　春夏と話をさせて。
いいわね。
Is that your condition for
telling me where Inori is?
それが　いのりの居場所を教える
交換条件ですか？
I'm sure she must know Gai's plan.
彼女なら
涯の計画を知っているはず。→
あの人を知りたい。
I want to know him.
His past, his desires,
his weaknesses, his pain... Everything.
彼の過去も
望みも　弱みも　痛みも　全て。
（春夏）《供奉院家。
今は　もう　ここしか…》
The Kuhouins... I've got nowhere else to go now.
あっ！
（倉知）桜満　春夏博士ですね。
Dr. Haruka Ouma, am I right?
（倉知）お久しぶりです　春夏さん。
It's been a long time, Haruka.
倉知さん！
Kurachi?!
追われていると聞き
いらっしゃるのではないかと…。
When I heard you were on the run,
I thought you might come here.
少し問題をね…。
I have a slight problem.
でも　もう　あそこは
供奉院の館ではないんです。
However... I'm afraid that isn't
the Kuhouin mansion any longer.
Then Mr. Kuhouin?
じゃあ　供奉院翁は…。
It was a hero's death.
ご立派な最期でした。
I tried to kill Mana to prevent
Daath from carrying out its plan.
（春夏）ダアトの計画を防ぐために
真名を撃とうとしたのよ。→
でも　失敗だった。
But I failed.
Wait a moment. I thought Mana was...
（倉知）待ってください。
真名って　確か…。
My daughter, yes.
（春夏）私の娘よ。
（大雲）つまり
集のお姉さんですか。
Shu's older sister, in other words?
知ってるの？　集のこと。
（大雲）自分は葬儀社の人間です。
You know Shu?
I'm a member of Funeral Parlor.
そう　葬儀社の…。
Funeral Parlor, I see...
What was Shu like?
集は　どんな子だった？
私　母親なのに
ほったらかしだったから。
I am his mother, but I'm afraid I neglected him...
いえ　そうじゃない。
No, that's not it.
逃げていたのね　私は…。
Really I've been running
away from him, haven't I?
春夏は　本当の母親じゃないんだ。
Haruka isn't my real mother.
父さんと再婚して…。
She got remarried to my dad...
But he died right away.
でも　すぐに
父さんは死んじゃって。
She raised me anyway, though.
それでも　僕を
ずっと育ててくれた。
It wasn't a sense of duty or anything.
I really did care about Shu.
義務感とかじゃなかった。
私は　本当に　集が　かわいかったの。
（春夏）親を亡くした　集と
あの人を亡くした　私。→
Shu lost a parent, and I lost him...
でも　私たち２人は…。
Still, the two of us were...
（春夏）そうね。　ただ　ずっと→
Yes, perhaps we were only
licking each other's wounds all along.
２人で　傷を　なめ合ってきた
だけなのかもしれない。
（嘘界）うん…。→
Hmm. Then you can assure me that
building is a Funeral Parlor hideout?
では　あのビルが葬儀社の隠れ家で間違いないのですね？
（女性）は…　はい。
Y-Yes...
I can't hear you!
聞こえません！
（女性）う…　嘘じゃないです！
I-I'm not lying! Please believe me!
信じてください！！
≪（電子音）
I'm picking up a signal, Sir. It's the real thing.
反応を捉えました。
間違いありません。
Magnificent. You're an honest woman.
素晴らしい。
あなたは正直者だ。
あっ…！
（嘘界）これは　ほんのお礼です。
This is just a small token of my thanks.
≪（銃声）
Someone's here.
誰か来た。
≪（足音）
≪（ノック）
Excuse me, but we heard
there was vaccine here...
≪（男性）すみません。　こちらに
ワクチンがあると聞いたのですが。
How much would you charge for some?
（男性）幾らで
分けてもらえますか？→
We heard the government's
stores are running out...
政府のワクチンは
なくなるって聞いて。
I have two young children at home! Please!
うちには　小学生の子供が
２人いるの。　お願い！
You want to keep it all to
yourself, don't you? Despicable!
独り占めするつもりだな。
汚いぞー！
- Yeah, he's right!
- Come out and face us!
（男性）そうだ　そうだ！
（男性）出てこい！
- Open this door!
- We said we'd pay you!
（男性）扉を開けろ！
（男性）金なら払うって言ってんだ！
誤解です。　ここには
ワクチンなんてありませんよ。
You're mistaken. There's no vaccine here.
- Liar!
- You can't fool us!
≪だまされるか！
≪本当にないのか見せてみろ！
Show us you really don't have any!
（大雲）分かりました。→
All right. I'll open the door,
so come see for yourselves.
開けますから
その目で見てください。
See? It's just an office.
（大雲）ほら。
ただの事務所ですよ。
There's no vaccine anywhere...
ワクチンなんて　どこにも…。
損ですね。　正義の味方は。
Being a champion of justice just doesn't pay.
（悲鳴）
（大雲）うっ！
大雲！
Ogumo!
Don't worry about me! Just run!
構うな！　脱出しろ！！
春夏さんも。
You too.
（大雲）うおおぉぉー！
（大雲）ぐっ！
おぉ…。
（大雲）貴様はー！
You bastard!
Too bad, so sad.
残念でした。
We seem to be short two...
（嘘界）２人　足りませんか。
戻らなくていいの？
Shouldn't we go back?
It's dangerous for us to go.
Let's try asking a different team.
私たちが行くのは　危険です。
別部隊に　要請してみましょう。
これは何なんですか？
What is this?
最後の希望よ。
The last hope.
Don't tell me it's?!
まさか！？　これって…。
A Void Genom. Our last...
（春夏）ヴォイドゲノム。
私たちに残された　最後の…。
そして　最悪の希望。
...and worst hope.
（男性）やっぱり　無理なんだよ。
あの涯と　やり合うなんて。
Look, there's just no way we can take on Gai!
What, this doesn't get your goat at all?!
お前　悔しくないのかよ！
けど　大雲さんも
やられたっていうし。
But even Ogumo got taken down...
We've only lost contact with him.
Argo's out checking on him right now.
（綾瀬）連絡が
取れなくなっただけよ。
今　アルゴが確認に行ってる。
（鶫）具合は　どう？
How is he?
（花音）少しずつ進行してる。
Getting worse little by little.
Can't anything be done?
何とか　ならないの？
ごめん。　ステージ３以上は
私たちのワクチンじゃ…。
I'm sorry. Once they hit Stage III,
our vaccine isn't strong enough...
Argo's back!
≪アルゴが戻ってきたぞ！
What about Gumy?
雲っちは？　一緒じゃないの？
He's not with you?
Yeah, he's with me.
（アルゴ）一緒だよ。
（鶫）えっ？　でも…。
But...
（アルゴ）一緒なんだ。
He's with me.
ハッ！　嘘…　でしょ？
No... way...
ごめんなさい。
私を守って…。
I'm sorry. He was protecting me.
No...
そんな…！
雲っち…。
Gumy!
How far you've fallen, Gai.
（四分儀）ぶざまですね　涯。→
Five years ago in that hell
on the African battlefront,
私は　５年前のアフリカ戦線。→
あの地獄の中→
I saw a natural talent in the
child soldier who tried to kill me.
自分を殺そうとした少年兵に
天稟を見ました。→
I've worked to make you king ever since.
以来　私は　あなたを王にすべく
働いてきた。→
However... Is this what
you wanted, Gai Tsutsugami?
だが　恙神　涯！→
あなたが望んだのは　こんな醜悪な偶像となることだったのか！
To become the unsightly idol you are now?
I've only ever had one goal, then and now.
（涯）俺の目的は
今も昔も　たった１つ。
そこで　お前たちが→
You lot chose to build dreams on it
勝手に夢を見て
勝手に失望しただけのこと。
and then chose to be disappointed, that's all.
All right, what was Funeral Parlor to you, then?
では！　あなたにとって→
葬儀社とは　われわれの戦いとは
何だったのです！？
What was our fight for?
知りたいか？
Do you want to know?
（四分儀）フッ！→
And yet, believe it or not,
I thought of you as a friend.
それでも　私は　あなたを
友だと思っていましたよ。
王に　友などいない。
いるのは　部下であり　駒だけだ。
A king has no friends.
He only has subordinates. Pawns.
（四分儀）では　駒として→
Then as one of your pawns,
I suppose I should express my gratitude.
それでも　あなたには
感謝を申し上げておきましょう。
おかげで　私に
新たな願望が生まれました。
Thanks to you, I have a new wish:
To kill you.
あなたを殺すことです。
（綾瀬）どうぞ。
Here.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
If I used that, could I fight Gai?
それを使えば　涯と戦えますか？
At the very least,
you'd gain the same power he has.
少なくとも　同じ力は手に入るわ。
でも…。
But...
全身の遺伝子から　おびただしい
拒絶反応が出る可能性もあるわ。
It's possible that every gene in your body
would have an extreme rejection reaction.
ひどい人間よね。
集には使わせたくないくせに→
I'm a horrible person, hmm?
I don't want to let Shu use it,
but I do want to have someone use it.
誰かには使ってもらいたいと
思ってるのよ。
（綾瀬）少しだけ分かります。
I can understand that a little.
Because I've seen Shu suffer
because of his power, too.
私も　集が力のせいで苦しむのを
見てきましたから。
（春夏）それだけじゃないの。
It's not just that.
もし　もう一度　使えば
おそらく　あの子は死ぬわ。
If he used it again, he'd probably die.
ハッ！
それだけ危険なものなの。
That's how dangerous it is.
≪（爆発音）
（春夏・綾瀬）あっ！
派手にいきましょう。
今日はパーティーです！
Let's pull out all the stops.
Today is a party!
≪（爆発音）
あっ！
（亞里沙）遅かったみたいね。
It looks like we're too late.
あっ！
≪（ブレーキ音）
（亞里沙）待ちなさい！　桜満　集！
Hold it right there, Shu Ouma!
春夏！
Haruka!
Leave me... behind...
（颯太）置いてけ…。
（谷尋）黙ってろ。
Just shut up. I don't want
to abandon anyone anymore.
（谷尋）俺は　もう
誰も見捨てたくない。
Yahiro...
（花音）谷尋…。
No need to hold back!
Make the bullets pour down like rain!
（嘘界）遠慮は　いりません。　さぁ！
雨のような銃弾を！
嵐のような　じゅうりんを！
Lay waste to them like a storm!
駄目。　誰とも連絡が取れない。
It's no use... I can't contact anyone.
（アルゴ）戻るしかねえ。
We'll have to go back.
えっ…。　でも　戻ったら
挟み撃ちに遭うよ！
But if we go back, we'll be
caught in a pincer attack!
（アルゴ）
なら　どうしろってんだよ！
Then what do you suggest?!
すまねえ…。
Sorry.
Dr. Ouma, please use the Void Genom on me.
桜満博士。　私に
ヴォイドゲノムを使ってください。
Shu once gave me the courage
and power to stand up and fight.
私は　以前　集から→
立ち上がる勇気と力を
もらいました。→
だから　今度は
自分で立ち上がりたいんです。
So this time, I want to stand up on my own.
たとえ
涯と討ち合うことになっても！
Even if it means a shootout with Gai!
綾姉。　いきなり　何で…。
Aya, where is this coming from?!
It's okay. I've been
thinking about this for a while.
大丈夫。　前から考えてたの。
お願いします！
Please!
Oh no you don't!
≪（嘘界）させませんよ～！
≪（銃声）
≪（嘘界）
製造されたアンプルは　３つ。
Three ampules were produced.
I've been searching for the
remaining one for quite some time.
残りは　どこにあるのか
ずっと捜していたのですが→
I might have known you had it, Dr. Ouma.
やはり　あなたでしたか　桜満博士。
あれは　私が頂戴します。
I'll be taking it now.
To do what with?
（綾瀬）それで　どうするの？
（嘘界）私はねぇ　見たいんです。→
I want to behold it, you see:
that mystical and sublime light.
あの　不可思議かつ崇高な光を。
きっと　あの光の向こうには
真理がある。
I'm quite sure the truth lies beyond that light.
Yes, I dare say I would do anything to have it!
そのためならば　私は
何だって　してしまうでしょう！
うん？
（綾瀬）一生　語ってなさい！！
Talk yourself blue in the face!
うっ！
（嘘界）この　おてんばさん！
Why, you little tomboy!
I won't let you have it!
渡しません！
（綾瀬）あっ！
フフフフ。　あっ。
あっ！
ほぉ！
集！
（谷尋）集…！
- Shu!
返して！　集。
それが何だか分かってるの！？
Give it back, Shu.
Do you understand what that is?!
もちろんだよ　綾瀬。
全ては　ここから始まったんだ。
Of course I do, Ayase. Everything started here.
これは　やっぱり
僕が背負うべき罪なんだ。
I should be the one who
bears the burden of this sin.
No! That's our sin!
（春夏）違う！
それは　私たちの罪よ！
二度目はないのよ　集。
ヴォイドの力が　あなたを殺すわ！
There won't be a second time, Shu!
Void power will kill you!
ありがとう　母さん。
Thanks, Mom.
えっ…。
本物の親子じゃなくても→
Even if we're not real mother and son,
I'm glad I got to be with you.
僕は　母さんと一緒にいられて
よかった。
今は　本当に　そう思うよ。
I really feel that way, now.
でも　これが→
But you see...
僕にできる　唯一のことだから。
This is the one thing I can do.
集！！
Shu!
駄目ぇぇぇ！！
Don't!
ぐっ…。　うわ…！
うわぁぁぁぁぁぁぁ！！
（嘘界）そう！
これですよ　これ　これ！
Yes, this is it! This, this!
あぁ…！
（いのり）駄目！　集！
No, Shu!
I might have known it would be you.
やはり　お前なのか！
ずっと　逃げてきたんだ。
I've been running away all this time.
でも　僕は
今こそ　僕を　さらけ出す！
But right here, right now,
I'm going to reveal myself!
右手が！
His right hand!
（春夏）あぁ…　集！
Shu...
A royal gun salute to mark the king's birth!
王の誕生に祝砲を！
I'm sorry, Ayase.
ごめん　綾瀬。
あっ…。
集。
Shu...
No need to hold back!
Fire every bullet you've got!
（嘘界）遠慮は　いりません。
全弾　ぶち込みなさい！
♪♪～
（谷尋）ハッ！
（颯太）集…！
Shu...
都合のいい話だけど→
I know this is selfish and inconsiderate,
but would you let me rely
on your powers one last time?
もう一度だけ　君たちの力を
当てにさせてもらえないかな。
集…。　お前…！
Shu, you...
♪♪～
≪（トレーラーの走行音）
Shu Ouma!
桜満　集君。
これなら　どうですかーっ！
How about this?
うおぉぉぉぉぉ！
おおっ！
殺せるんですか？　あなたに。
Do you have it in you to kill me?
I've decided.
僕は決めたんです。
うん？
みんなのために
この身を汚しきるって。
I'll get my hands as dirty
as I have to, for their sakes.
It's inside me...
Inside me, another person's heart...
入ってる…！
私の中に　他人の心が！
ヴォイドの光がぁぁぁ！
...the Void light!
♪♪～
ハッ…。　集！！
Shu!
（アルゴ）あっ…。
あぁ！
集…！
Shu!
あっ　見て！→
Look!
集の体…。
（谷尋）キャンサー！
Shu's body!
The cancer?
さっきまで　なかったのに。
（颯太）俺のだ。
But it wasn't there a second ago!
It's mine.
えっ？　あっ！
（颯太）
あれは　俺のキャンサーなんだ。
That's my cancer.
（谷尋）じゃあ　集のヴォイドは…。
Then Shu's Void is?
His Void gathers everything
and assumes its weight.
あいつのヴォイドは
全てを集めて引き受ける。
強さも弱さも　光も闇も　全て。
Strengths, weaknesses,
light, darkness... Everything.
集…。
それが　あなたの運命だというの？
Shu... Are you telling me that's your destiny?
それも　貴様の遺志だというのか
クロス。
Are you telling me that's your will too, Kurosu?
《悲しみを　アポカリプスが
悪意に変えるなら→
If Apocalypse turns misery into bad will,
I'll assume that bad will, too.
僕は　その悪意も引き受ける》
The bad will can sink into my body.
《この体に
悪意が溶けてしまえばいい》
《いのり。　今　行くよ》
I'm coming, Inori.
♪♪～
What am I supposed to care about,
left behind alone in a world like that?
I spent so many days,
accumulated so many feelings
And you were by my side the whole time,
A fixture of my life, and when you left,
I discovered their weight for the first time
If I'd gripped your hand tight
that day and not let go...
In the end, I was only living
in my own self-satisfied world
"Now it's like I'm a liar
for saying I did it all for you"
Even those murmured words don't reach you
Run, run to you
Watch, I'll fall as often,
get lost as often as it takes
Wait for me, because I'm on my way
No matter what difficulties are waiting there